VIGNESHWAR PERUMAL

Email: pvignesh3000@gmail.com Phone: (281) 410-5416 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vigneshwar-perumal/

Vigneshwar has more than 5 years of experience as a data analytics expert. He has a strong ability to extract, manipulate, and analyze complex sets of data to provide insights across a broad range of business needs and target audiences using SQL, Python, R, MATLAB, and Mathematica. He has extensive experience in producing reports (Jupyter and RMarkdown) and presentations (Slides and PowerPoint), as well as using business intelligence and visualization tools (Microsoft Excel, Tableau, Google Looker Studio, and PowerBI). Additionally, he has a proven track record of proactively identifying problems/opportunities and determining solutions, as well as strong project management skills and the ability to work effectively both as an individual contributor and as a part of a team.

CAREER EXPERIENCE

Innovations Analyst, Pinterest, New York City, NY

Mar. 2023 to Present

- Supporting data science workstreams by employing quantitative analysis and data visualization skills using Python, SparkSQL and PrestoSQL to further up level insights deliverables that help advertisers succeed on clients.
- Creating methods and tools powering insights-based narratives that help marketers understand their opportunity on client and plan their media campaigns via data-backed recommendations on keywords, creative, targeting, and timing, leading to an improvement in campaign performance for clients.
- Designing and executing querying and analysis of first party platform data to make recommendations that impact advertisers' business objectives on clients for key industries and audiences using PrestoSQL, SparkSQL, Python, Flohub, Tableau, Looker Studio and Jupyter notebooks.

Senior Data Analyst, EDG, Edison, NJ

Nov. 2020 to Jan. 2023

- Implemented Logistic Regression, Linear Regression, Time Series Analysis, Decision Trees, and other Machine Learning methods to model and optimize sales across multiple geographical regions, products, and channels.
- · Defined and built data pipelines that enable faster, better, data informed decision making within the business using Dataiku.
- Extensively contributed to data science strategy and roadmap, collaborating with other scientists, ML engineers, and program managers on the execution of the roadmap.
- · Built compelling data stories and visualizations, skillfully transforming complex data into actionable narratives for decision-makers, resulting in a 6.5% increase in sales.

Digital Consulting Analyst, Accenture, Houston, TX

Sept. 2019 to Oct. 2020

- Built strong relationships with clients, understanding their data needs, and delivering data-driven insights that informed decision making and drove business growth.
- Utilized expertise in tools such as SQL, Python, R, Radiant, D3.js and data visualization platforms to extract, manipulate and analyze complex data sets, and effectively communicated findings to stakeholders, including management and technical leads.
- · Worked closely with analysts, developers, and other data scientists to develop powerful analyses, models, and analytical solutions in a fast-paced environment.
- · Worked with other functional teams to evaluate new data sources and advised on data format and data dictionary.
- · Programmed using Python and libraries such as NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn and Statsmodel.

FORMAL EDUCATION

- · M.S. in Business Analytics from Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA (2024)
- · Professional Certificate Program in Data Science, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA (2019)
- B.S. in Biomedical Engineering, School of Engineering, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ (2019)

CERTIFICATIONS

- · HackerRank Certified in Advanced SOL.
- · HackerRank Certified in R programming.
- · HackerRank Certified in Python.
- · Dataiku Certified ML Core Designer.
- · Google Analytics for Beginners.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Data Science Languages: Python, R, MySQL, MATLAB, Mathematica, Tableau, PowerBI, Dataiku, D3.js

Operating Systems: Linux, Unix, Windows, MacOS, iOS and Android Open-Source IDE: RStudio, PyCharm, Visual Studio, Jupyter Notebooks

Productivity Tools: Sub Lime Editor, Putty, WinSCP, FileZilla, Microsoft Office Tools, WebEx, GoToMeeting, Team

Viewer, Skype, Share Point, Zoho, Salesforce, CopperCRM, Quotewerks, Asana, Mailchimp and

Zapier, Camtasia, SFTP, FileZilla, Coda and Google Apps